传家之宝黎架，你掟咗你赔呀
It's an heirloom, pay up if you scratch it.
传你老豆呀
Nonsense, I remember that suitcase.
呢个急我明明见你旧年
You discovered it abandoned by someone...
喺机场见唔到人攞
at the airport.
自己挞咗返黎唧
And you brought it home.
仲成个急系咸鱼，臭到冤添
It stinks like an old fish now.
坚叔，讲吓笑啫
Uncle Kin I was only joking.
讲笑
Joking?
不过你炒咗我，你都冇乜好处架
You have nothing to gain if you fire me.
六四之后生意淡薄
Business is bad after the June the 4th crackdown.
交通灯，唔准笑
Don't laugh. Traffic light.
佢哋走晒啰，移哂民啰
They've all emigrated.
连我都走埋，你好闷架喎
If I leave you too you're going to be bored.
我个个月出粮俾你，我咪仲闷
I'm even more bored having to pay you each month.
哦，咁你即系唔俾面我啫
Why don't you give me any face then?
好啰喎
Stop it.
对不起，两位
Sorry.
你只蟹呀
Your crab.
是你的      不好意思
- It's yours. - Sorry.
唔阻两位咩？
Am I interrupting?
哦，唔阻，有何贵干？
Oh, no. What can I do for you?
呢度有间沾记车行喺扑正街二号架
There's a Jim Kee Garage at 2 Pok Ching Street.
唔知喺边度呢，呵？
You know where?
小姐，就系呢度喇，扑正街二号
Miss, here it is, 2 Pok Ching Street.
系喎
Oh yes,
我就系呢间车行董事长，总经理
I'm the president and general manager of this garage
兼总工程师，我叫刘定坚，刘博士
and concurrently chief mechanic. I'm Dr. Lau Ting Kin.
我系佢老细
I'm his boss.
你唔好理佢，佢傻唧
Don't listen to him, he's out of his mind.
我攞车黎俾你整
I'm your client,
算唔算系你老细呀？
ain't I your boss?
你有车咩？
Have you got a car?
梗系有喇
Sure,
唔该你同我整到佢会行为止
please make it run.
呢度咁屈质，我哋去饮杯茶，黎呀
It's so humble here, let's go for tea, come on.
亚贞、亚文、亚德
Ching, Man, Tack.
文文姨呀
Auntie Man.
呀，文文乜甘早呀你
Man you're so early.
姐夫
Brother-in-law.
呢个四眼佬，咁熟口熟面唧
This four eyes looks familiar.
文文亚姨      姐夫
- Auntie Man. - Brother-in-law.
文文姨呀，有冇睇过我哋间新铺呀？
Auntie Man have you seen my new shop?
未呀
No.
你睇吓，就系呢度喇
Look, it's here.
哦，我认得你喇
Well, I remember now.
哈，你咪刘定坚个契弟？
Aren't you Lau Ting Kin's god brother?
哗，死人口水沾
You're bloody Bluffer Jim.
唔见你几十年，仲咁多口水架你？
You haven't changed after all these years.
也咁折堕呀？搞到帮人整车呀
Poor fellow, now you've sunk to a repairer.
咩呀？你好巴闭呀？
What, what do you then?
哦，失礼，我喺隔离开车行啫
I'm the boss of the garage next to you.
咁又唔系同人整车？
Why aren't you repairing a car then?
唔驶我整喎，我有三个女
I have three daughters who can help me.
Uncle
Uncle.
喂，睇你三个女咁靓
They're all so beautiful.
我谂冇个系你生架喇
They can't be yours.
唉，我老婆死咗喇，你唔好屈佢呀
My wife is dead, don't use her name in vain.
吓，乜本来爱我
Oh, Ting Ting was my flame...
但系嫁咗俾你个婷婷死咗呀
but she died after marrying you.
错，佢一直系爱我
She was always in love with me.
系你自作多情缠住嗰个婷婷死咗啫
You entangled her and she died as a result.
岂有此理，以前你又抢走我爱人
Outrageous. First you took away my love,
等我终身不娶
and made me a life long bachelor,
而家仲喺我隔离开间车行黎顶我
and now you're my competitor in the garage business.
我何止顶你吓，直情顶到你执笠添嘛
Sure, I'll make you go broke.
睇吓边个执先喇
We'll see which of us will go broke first.
我帮你顶冧佢
Let me help you compete against him.
唔驶你帮
I don't need your help.
好，一于请几只狼番黎，沟哂你啲女
I'll bring in a few wolves to ruin your daughters.
罗家铃，罗家铃呀
Lo Kar Ling, Lo Kar Ling.
喂，罗家铃
Hey, Lo Kar Ling.
乜嘢事呀，班主
What's the matter? Boss.
今次我俾机会你做文武生
I'll give you the lead role.
你唔好搞喎我台戏呀
Don't ruin my show
唔系我炒你鱿鱼架
or I'll fire you.
哎...班主呀
Boss.
我忽然好紧张，唔记得晒啲台词呀
I'm nervous, I've forgotten my lines.
我攞个剧本睇睇先吓
Let me read the script again.
攞攞攞，攞你条命咩
Crazy. It's too late now.
而家先话唔记得，出去爆肚喇
Go and ad-lib.
你冇事喇嘛？
Are you alright?
冇事！死喇
Yes. Oh, no.
你大镬，确大镬，撞到亚姐头鄂鄂
You're in trouble, you hit me hard.
若然亚姐发烂渣
If I get nasty
你着牛皮裤都嫌薄都嫌薄
your pants are finished.
I'm sorry，I'm sorry
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
而家后悔已经迟，最多俾你嘴番啖
Don't repent now, at worst I'll let you hug me.
你做契妈，我做Baby做Baby
You be the godmother I'll be the baby.
我呸，你生爱滋，人白痴
You're crazy, you're crazy, you've got AIDS.
个头大过Kenny B，个脑细只过蚊
You're head's bigger than Kenny B but your mind's like a baby's.
搞到亚姐出晒丑
You've made me lose face.
我一枪射到你冇得医，冇得医
I'll shoot you till you're finished.
班主，我...
Boss, I...
唉，你唔驶旨意再喇
Well, don't expect to go on anymore.
哎吔吔，No...I'm fire呀
Oh no, I've been fired.
老婆  老婆
Darling, darling.
坏  老公回来了
Bad, my husband's returning.
不是吧  老公
No? Darling.
快点着衫喇
Get dressed quickly.
喂 老婆
Oh, darling.
头先呢  我在那里看到一套家私  好正啊
Just now I saw a set of excellent furniture.
老公啊 呢张床唔错
Darling, this bed is not bad.
我刚刚睡觉过的  朱生嘿
No. I'm just slept on it, mr.Chu.
係呀
Oh, yes.
係喇  双人床又衬色  你俩个最合睡噶
Hey, this double bed matches in color and suits you best.
死肥仔 勾引我老婆
Damn fatty, you're seducing my wife.
吔吔吔  你讲吔  有吔嘢证据啊
What... what did you say? Have you got any proof?
证据？ 队咗超人之外
Proof? You're the 2nd man after Superman who
你係第二个将底裤着在出边啲人
wears the underpants inside out.
三合会会籍审裁处
The tribunal for crasing the membership of the triad society.
望吔嘢？ 未呗人斩过  我劈你咸家惨
Don't stare. Have you never been chopped? Damn your whole family.
先填咗张表住喇
Fill in the form now.
填吔嘢真啊
Nonsense.
我来洗底你就同我洗
I'm here to have my criminal records removed.
你唔同我洗我斩你咸家惨
Now do it for me or I'll chop all your family.
洗  洗
Okay, okay.
走开喇  唔係劈死你嘎
Don't state or I'll chop you dead.
"Please open"
请将你美丽的面庞放入去
please put your beautiful face in.
Angel  你係我心目中的天使
Angel, you're an angel in my eyes.
估下我係边个
Guess who I am?
史泰龙
Stallune?
唔係
No.
成龙
Jackie?
都唔係
No.
我係你生命之人  陈卫健先生
I'm your faithful servant, weakling chen.
我可以惜你吗
May I kiss you?
Excuse me
Excuse me.
唔好啊
Don't!
打死你啊
I beat you
救命啊
help!
坐...饮茶
Sit down, Have some tea.
大表哥、二表哥、三表弟、四表弟
Hello, Guys.
饮茶...
Have some tea...
饮茶，饮茶...
呢排喺边度发财呀？
How have you been getting on?
咪又系咁
So-so.
老实讲呀，其实呢轮我都失业呀
Frankly I'm now out of a job.
其实我都系呀
Me too.
咁呢餐边个请呀？
Who'll pay for this meal then?
大表哥呀，其实讲起有大食大
Cousin, the elder should pay.
呢餐应该系食你架喇，呀？
This should be your treat.
你哋冇啲同情心架
Have you no sympathy.
我已经洗底做好人架喇
I've already decided to go straight.
又唔可以劈人，又唔可以屈人
I can't chop or frame anyone anymore.
又唔可以放贵利
I can't charge high interest either.
冇晒啲谋生技能
I've no more means of making a living.
你哋当造福社会
Please, for heaven's sake,
请我饮餐茶好唔好？
Pay for this.
如果一定要我埋单唧
You may drive me to desperation
我落去劏死牛架
if you insist I pay for this.
冷静，冷静，冷静
Keep cool, keep cool.
在下得罪咗阿姐呀
I've offended big sister, anymore.
喺粤剧界都难以立足架喇
I have no standing in the Cantonese Opera world anymore.
各位表兄呀，以在下歌喉
Cousins, with a good voice like mine
可以改做咩剧呢？吓？
what other acting can I do?
默剧呀
Mime.
二表哥呀，我觉得我哋四个之中
Cousin,
最似有钱佬唧都系你喎
of us four you look the richest.
你话似就似架喇，吓？
No way.
我够似秦汉啰，又唔见林青霞钟意我
I look like Chin Han but I have no lover like Liu Ching Hsia.
我够似尔冬升啰
I look like Erin Tung Shung.
又唔见张曼玉钟意我
But I have no lover like Cheung Man Yuk.
我够似刘德华啰，又唔见...
I look like Lau Tack Wah but...
呀，边个呀？边个呀？
Who is it? Who is it?
又唔见麦当娜钟意我
And why doesn't Madonna like me?
唓你九噏
All bloody nonsense.
我有边句唔系九噏架
I've been muttering nothing but nonsense.
哎，大家唔好晒气喇，若姐
Well, let's not argue anymore. Yo.
当你敬老，请我哋三个饮茶，吓？
You be the host in respect of the three elders okay?
有乜理由我喎
Why?
因为你的名字是弱者，冇得上诉
Because your name is frailty and you can't complain.
唉，十字街头
Oh, on the crossroads.
不知何去何从呀
I don't know which way to go.
如果我系女人，我一定下海做舞女
If I were a girl I'd become a taxi dancer.
你咁唧样，如果系女人呀，跳海就得
With looks like yours you'd be done for.
劈你冚家富
Damn you.
唉，睇下嗰边
Oh look, over there.
喂，咩呀？
What is it?
写住啲咩呀？
What does it say?
耶稣救世人，坚叔救港人
Jesus saves. Uncle Kin saves Hong Kong.
帮坚叔整车，唔怕坦克车
Have your car fixed by Kin, you need fear no tanks.
坚叔助你移民，唔怕冇得松人
He helps you emigrate and be free.
哎，如此着数，做坚记可以买屋先喎
So many benefits. You could buy a house if you worked here.
梗系喇
Of course.
你就系坚叔呀？
Aren't you uncle Kin?
你哋唔驶讲咁多喇
Well, if you hadn't told me,
我知你哋黎应征架
I would have known you were looking for work.
虽然呢次我铺头呢有成二千人报名
Although I've had 2000 applicants for only 4 vacancies
我只系录取四个 但系为咗俾啲机会你哋啲年轻人呢
I'll give you young men a chance
我仍然会同你哋面试唧，入黎呀
by giving you an interview. Come in.
喂，你也曾话过会帮我哋移民架喎
Hey, you promised to help me emigrate.
嗱，苏联同中国大陆
You'd have to choose countries other than the Soviet Union and China. First.
你哋肯定唔会去架喇
Even if it's the last one I'll follow.
咁你哋有冇一百万美金投资？
Can you afford an investment of US$1 million?
咁五十万呢？
What about half a million?
二十万有冇呀？
What about $200,000?
咁有冇大学毕业或者特殊技能呀？
Are you a university graduate and have you special skills?
咁你哋唔驶谂喇
Forget it then.
你哋只可以移民去两个地方
You can only emigrate to two places,
一个就去北极都
the north pole
一个就系非洲唧阿呢吉打
or Aricutta in Africa.
北极都每年夏天最热嗰日呢
The hottest temperatures in summer
就系零下一百一十度
is 110 below at north pole zero.
阿呢吉打
Aricutta.
嗰度唧天气呢就四季如春
It's like spring the four seasons,
啲女仔呢个个貌美如花
the girls are all beautiful like flowers,
周围都有生果架，唔驶做嘢架
fruits are abundant everywhere and you don't have to work.
在下要去阿呢吉打
I want to go to Aricutta.
但系嗰度唧爱滋病率达到百分之九十
But the AIDS rate is 90%
即系话每十个人呢有九个人有爱滋病
that means 9 AIDS sufferers out of 10 people.
留番俾你去喇
Well you'd better go then.
不过你哋唔驶担心唧
But don't worry,
只要签咗我呢份合约
if you sign this contract with us
唔止有个人唧福利
you'll not only get benefits
仲保证你哋 可以移民去世外桃源唧地方
but assurances of immigration to a paradise.
咁点呀？
What do you say?
做住先喇
Let's accept it for the time being.
你哋后生仔呢，真系冇法律常识唧
You young men have no legal common sense.
一日做几个钟，每个月几钱人工
You signed it
一年出几多个月粮
without asking about the working hours and the terms.
冚巴郎唔问就签嘞 好彩遇到我啫
Luckily you came upon me.
嗱，话你听喇，每日做十八个钟
Listen, you work 18 hours per day,
星期日做十七个钟
17 hours on Sundays
一年出十一个月粮
and get 11 months pay each year.
每年我生日嗰月呢，扣起上黎做人情
Your pay on the month of my birthday is deducted for my gift.
每人每个月唧人工就千三蚊
Your monthly wages are $1,300 each.
告一日假扣七百，迟到扣五百
$700 is deducted for one day's leave and $500 for late arrival.
头嗰六个月粮呢，就要黎做保证金唧
Your first six months pay will be deducted as security.
咁除咗同我整车之外
Besides fixing cars
仲要同我做啲家头细务
you've got to do household work for me
即系煮饭喇，洗衫喇咁，明咪？
like cooking and doing the laundry. Understand?
以前同人晒马，而家同人晒衫
Before you worked with horses, now you're a menial worker.
唉，折堕咯
You're well served.
靓女呀，四个靓女呀
Beautiful, four beautiful girls.
好靓咩，有你份咩？
Beautiful, but are they meant for us?
原来有啲咁笋唧嘢 我日日上黎晒衫都制咯
I don't mind coming up to hang clothes everyday now.
小生，这厢有礼呀
Young ladies our greetings to you.
大声点呀
Louder.
你唔得架喇，呢啲嘢等我黎呀
Can you do it? Let me help you.
喂，靓女，听唔听张国荣演唱会呀？
Hey beautiful, want to go to Cheung Kwok Wing's concert?
有飞多呀，握到手嗰啲呢！
I've got tickets, it's free.
喂，冇反应喎
Why no response?
会唔会系谭咏麟啲歌迷呀？
Could they be fans of Alan Tam?
正式屎坑口，冤夹臭
What a stinking mouth.
喂，佢哋可能扮嘢喎
Hey, they could be acting?
唔系喇，唔系喇，过去试一试佢喇
No, no. Go and test them out.
我先
I first.
末将亦愿意相随呀
I am willing to fallow you.
得番三条绳，实冇我份喇
Only three ropes left, I'll be counted out for sure.
梗有个人让人过去架嘛
Someone is going to shoot themselves over.
不过咁，助人为快乐之本
I'll do you a favor and let you go.
我俾你去喇
Okay, you go.
太感动喇
How touching
二表哥，你实在对我太好喇
You really are nice cousin.
去喇衰嘢
Go on bitch.
嗱，我数三声你哋飞过去吓
I'll count up to three and fly over.
一、二
1, 2,
二个半
2 and a half,
三，去啰
3, go
喂，朱玉干喂，做咩唔郁架
Hey Dried Pork why aren't we moving?
你搞乜鬼呀喂
What are you up to?
Kick住咗呀
It's stuck.
喂，快啲扯返我上去呀
Come on, pull me up now.
哎吔，弊喇，三条绳Kick住晒呀
Oh no, all three ropes are stuck.
我搵人救你哋呀
Let me get someone to help you.
快啲呀
Hurry up.
好快架喇
I will.
唔驶慌
Damn,
死仔包，一分钟唔返黎
he's still not back.
斩到你变免治牛肉
I'll mince him.
哎吔，弊喇，弊喇，条绳就黎甩喇
On no the rope's going to...
收声喇，屎坑口
Shut your stinking mouth.
救命呀，救命呀
Help, help.
冲凉呀？
Taking a bath?
呀，色狼呀
Sex fiends. Sex fiends.
色狼呀
Sex fiends.
哗，又多一件色狼呀
One more sex maniac.
又多件丑样色狼呀
One more ugly sex maniac.
咩色狼呀？我系飞虎队呀
What? I'm a member of the flying tiger squad.
飞虎队？
Flying tiger squad?
呢餐饱咯
He asked for it.
个色狼真系上咗黎呀，我哋预备
He really is coming up. Let's stand by.
Ok，等佢埋黎先喇
Okay, wait till he gets close.
一、二、三
1, 2, 3...
唉呀  坏喇
Oh my god! Look at that!
救命啊
Help!
咩係你啊  你还敢嚟找我
Oh, it's you! How dare you?
我唔想嘎
I didn't want to.
你个死仔啊
You bastard.
扮完超人扮Badman
You play a young man, a bad man.
好好睇咩
It's so exciting.
三位请喝茶
You're treating us to tea?
我们这座大厦里有贼啊
Are there burglars in here?
你咁叫法，有贼都俾你吓走喇
You would scare them off.
哎吔，好痛呀
Oh, it hurts.
老细，总部叫你返去喎
Boss, headquarters wants you back.
仲唔快啲返去？
Hurry up.
咁拉我入黎先喇
Get me in first.
你唔驶入黎喇
You don't have to.
Hello，各位街坊
Hello ladies and gentlemen.
今日沾记汽车公司正式开张
Today is the official opening of Jim Kee Garage.
专诚为各位街坊服务 新张期内全部七折
We offer 30% off all services.
呀，关公子黎咗呀
Mr. Kwan is here.
又系个烦友呀
It's that bore again.
行喇
Let's get going.
沾叔，请咗个新伙计咩？
Uncle Jim have you got a new employee?
唔系，我姨仔文文吖嘛
My sister-in-law Man.
关公子呀，亚贞、亚德、亚敏
Mr. Kwan, Ching, Tack, Mun.
过黎，过黎，介绍关公子你识
Come here, let me introduce you to Mr. Kwan.
呀，我三个女呀，呢位系关生
My three daughters Mr. Kwan.
Hi
Hi.
Hello，得闲无事，唔好黎坐
Hello, don't come round when you have time.
对唔住呀，我两个姐姐系咁架
Sorry, my two sisters are cranky,
你唔好见怪呀
please don't blame them.
唔紧要，你唔系咪得啰
I won't, anyway you're different.
我都系呀
Not any different.
死人，俾佢抢晒啲客添
Damn, he's taken away my customers.
喂...过黎
Hello... come here.
过去拉客
Go and tout for customers.
Hi，神父，你好，整车呀？
Hi father, want to have your car fixed?
系，不过...
Yes, but...
唔驶不过喇，整乜都得架
Don't hesitate, we can fix anything.
不过我话你听呀
I tell you,
千祈唔好帮衬佢哋呀
Don't ever patronize them,
佢哋Very渣架
their service is lousy.
而且佢哋又唔信上帝，不如帮衬我喇
And they don't believe in god, patronize us.
帮衬我整车有叉烧包送架
You get free barbecue pork buns from us too.
不过我架系单车
Mine's a bicycle.
哦，冇所谓，都杀
We can fix it all the same.
喂，过黎
Hey, come here.
喂，刘定坚
Hey, Lau Ting Kin.
你走过黎我呢度抢，真系唔通架喎
You've gone too far.
关你乜事啫，而家
Is this any of your business?
系上帝派神父落黎帮衬我整车
God has sent a priest to patronize us.
你唔钟意呢，同上帝投诉
Complain to god if you'd prefer.
唔好系度己己拮拮
You talk too much.
唔系呀，神父帮衬我
He's my customer.
我系教友黎架嘛，我日日都有念经架
I'm a Christian, I pray every day.
你应该帮衬教友至啱吖嘛
You should patronize a Christian.
神父，帮衬我，帮衬我便有叉烧包呀
Father patronize me and you'll get free barbecue pork buns.
唔好嘈，Don't argue，一个一个轮
Don't argue with each other.
你有轮，你又有轮
You have a wheel, you have a wheel too.
唔得，神父
No.
唔得，两个轮都系我架
No. They are both mine.
我架
Is mine.
哎吔，你哋整烂我两个轮
You've damaged my wheels,
我以后都冇轮用
I can't use it anymore.
冇事
It's alright.
我冇事，帮我郁佢
Yes, get him.
乜你四个唔系飞虎队咩？
Aren't you members of the flying tigers squad?
咩？咩飞虎队？
Flying tiger squad?
咩呀？点你唔得呀，吓？
Well, can't I do that?
咬我个头吖，我个头够硬呀
Bite my head, it's hard.
咬我心口吖，我心口有胸骨
Bite my chest, it has bones.
咬我肚腩吖，我肚腩够韧
Bite my potbelly, it's tough.
咬我
Bite me.
我唔讲嗰度得唔得呀
I don't want to say that.
嗰度唔咬得架
Don't bite that.
你吔屎喇
You're damned.
唉，我冇轮用咯
I have no more wheels.
咩事呀？
What happened?
个刘定坚啰
Lau Ting-Kin
同埋嗰四只死仔过黎抢我生意呀
and those four bastards came to snatch my business.
驶乜同啲未受过教育唧人劳气啫
Don't waste your time on these ignorant people.
呢间铺应该归我间地产公司唧
This is the property of my property company.
我听日就落Order，加佢三十倍租
Tomorrow I'll announce a rent rise of 30 times.
咩话？我研究你阿妈个内脏呀？
What, did I offend your mother?
驶咩劳气啫，劳气都冇用唧
There's no point in getting excited.
喂，咩事先？
Hey, what's up?
唔好黎呀，唔好乱黎
Don't try anything foolish.
唔驶怕有我喺度
Don't worry I'm here.
小心呀
Watch out.
有冇搞错，咁臭唧
It stinks,
臭走晒我哋啲客呀
it scared all the customers off.
臭晕埋我个妹添喎，走喇，走呀
And my sister's in a coma too. Go now.
走呀
Go now.
你好嘢
You did it.
唏，岂有此理，郁我米饭班主
How dare you lay hands on my boss.
喂，你算点呀？
Hey, what's the idea?
何止呀，郁埋你添呀，死喇你
I'll get you too, damn you.
喂，过黎帮拖呀
Hey, come and give me a hand.
唓，冇钱你郁呀
We will for some money.
我身上啲钱俾晒你哋呀
I'll give all my money to you.
哦，咁又唔同喇
That's different.
走迟一步嗱，阉猫咁阉你
If you hadn't had got away I would have castrated you.
喂，磅水喇
Hey, pay up.
得，我讲过俾，一定会俾架
Don't worry, I'll keep my promise.
吓，咩话？八毫子
What? 80 cents?
系呀，我身上从来唔多过十蚊唧
I only keep up to $10 in my pocket.
我同人借，好过人同我借嘛
I'd rather borrow then lend to others.
老豆你点呀？
Are you alright daddy?
姐夫你点呀？
How are you brother-in-law?
个刘定坚暗算我呀
Lau Ting Kin took me unawares.
岂有此理话，连我老豆都够胆打
How dare they beat my daddy.
攞士巴拿过去打佢
Get a spanner to hit them.
你哋唔好用士巴拿，过去打人喇
Don't use a spanner to fight.
呢啲咁唧人呀，唔驶客气架
Don't be nice to those kind of people.
啲男人呀，用士巴拿打唔死架
Men can't be killed with spanners.
用垒球棍喇      好
- Use a softball bat. - Okay.
点呀？
How can this be?
哎吔，好痛呀
It hurts.
唔好再打喇，我以后唔敢喇
It hurts, I won't do it again.
我以后唔反抗，我以后乜都应承你
I promise I won't resist anymore.
你唔好再打喇，唔该你
Don't hit me, please.
系啰，我最多我任你为所欲为
At worse I'll let you do anything you like.
乜原来老豆打到佢哋咁伤架
So, daddy has beaten them up.
大镬喇，如果佢哋瓜咗 老豆咪要坐监
If they die daddy might get jailed.
阿敏呀，快啲搵啲药黎 同佢哋包扎伤口喇
Man, get plasters to dress their wounds.
去睇吓佢哋咯
Go and see to them.
你点呀？
Are you alright?
死狗咁声呀，黎呀，黎呀
You howl like a dog. Come on.
争乜啫你，你伤得过我咩
You're not as badly hurt as I am.
我伤得咁惨，你可怜吓我喇
I'm badly hurt, pity me.
哦，你咁伤，咪等白车喇吓
Wait for the ambulance then.
行喇
Okay.
伤成咁，都唔理人
You don't care about how I suffer.
阴功啰，伤成咁
So poor.
等阵攞啲药黎敷吓佢喇，吓
I'll get some plasters for him in a minute.
你睇我哋外面咁伤，其实里面仲伤呀
In fact I'm suffering even more internally.
系咩？
Is that so?
心病还须心药医呀
A mental illness requires mental treatment.
哦，咁即系话
You mean that
如果我哋同你哋行街睇戏食饭
if we go out with you for a meal
就会好番晒喇
and a movie you'll recover.
系呀，系呀，系呀
Right, right, right.
‘悭啲喇
It's too expensive.
买后座好喇，超等三十蚊好贵架
Buy back stalls, $30 is too much for loge.
发达咯
I'm lucky.
喂，唔好咁开心呀，因住有阴谋呀
Don't laugh, it could be a trick.
等我出去睇吓先喇
Let me go out and see.
文文呀，文文
Man Man, Man Man.
咩事呀？
Yes?
其实，你个样好似你家姐婷婷
You look like your bigger sister Ting.
我一见亲你，我就谂起佢
I think of her when I see you.
你唔好咁喇
Don't.
唔系呢，我好想你俾个机会
I wish I had...
等我同你单独倾吓偈
a chance to chat to you alone
当系我对你家姐最后一种怀念
to show my feelings for your bigger sister.
真唧？唔得呀
You mustn't.
我家姐都死咗咁多年咯
My sister died years ago.
仲讲佢，闷唔闷啲呀
Isn't it boring talking about her now?
你唔好咁老套喇
Don't be loutish.
如果想约我唧
Wait for me in the street
就七点半钟喺街口等我喇
at 7:30 if you want to date me.
哗，发达咯
Oh, I'm lucky.
嗱，我呢个沟女式设计好正架
My methods of seducing girls are great.
我准备寄去日本，睇吓有冇车厂肯买
I'm sending it to Japan to see if any garage will buy it.
咩咁巴闭呀？
What's so special?
梗系巴闭喇，个女仔一上汽车
Once a girl gets in,
安全第一扣，就解唔开架喇
the seat belt, once fastened, can't be undone.
咁，佢越禁掣就越紧
It gets tighter and tighter.
嗱，为咗避免沟错女起见
To avoid seducing the wrong girl,
仲有一上车呢，有四盏射灯射住佢喇
lights will shine on her.
射灯一着
Once turned on,
哗，啲假牙、假眼挹毛、假发、假波
any dentures, false lashes, wigs,
全部见光死
padded bras are visible.
验明正身之后呢，一禁个掣啫
After the check up one push
张櫈述一声就变咗张床架喇
will turn the seat into a bed.
哗，又有柔和音乐、迷幻灯光
And there's soft music and laser lights.
仲有个设计架，仲有自动安全系统架
Another device is the automatic safety system.
包你哋唔会唔记得喇
It serves as a reminder to you.
咁岂不是可以沟尽天下唧美女
So you can mix with any girls in the world.
小生钟意呀
I love it.
架车咁寸，出街实俾人凸嗰喎
Such a fantastic car may cause vandalism.
唉，呢架车个车头同两边呢
The two sides of the bonnet...
就识喷啲红色唧漆油
can spray red paint and plastic bullets.
同埋胶子弹出黎唧 边个凸你射边个啰
Anyone scratching it will get hit.
仲有呀，个车尾呢 可以喷啲好臭唧气味出黎唧
And the rear of the car can emit a stinking smell.
边个砵你咪喷边个啰
It can shoot at anyone trying to beep you.
唉，仲有一样嘢呀
Besides,
车顶呢有两个喇叭
there are two loudspeakers on the top
可以用个咪同人嗌交
so you can quarrel with anyone.
一定唔够你大声唧
They'll definitely drown out any other sounds.
哦，呢样嘢我钟意呀
I like that.
咪...你一味沟上车，或者佢口臭呢
Well, what if she smelt bad
或者见光死呢，到时冇计架喎
or exposed her defects?
系喎
Right.
有唧，嗱，呢个掣一禁呢
Don't worry, pushing this button will catapult the person beside you
你旁边唧人，自然就会弹出去架喇
out of the car.
喂...你攞我设计图做咩呀？
Hey, why have you taken away my design?
呢架咁唧车落喺你四个色魔手上
If this car should fall into your sex fiend hands
香港啲无知少女仲有得净唧
any innocent girl in Hong Kong would be finished.
俾我试吓先喇
Let me try.
嗱，限你三日整架出黎
I give you three days to turn one out.
做呢架车起码三十万架
This car costs at least $300,000.
你唔去死，三十万，三千蚊搞弄佢
Hell, $30,000, $3,000 will fix it.
三千蚊？
$3,000?
冇得讲，冇得上诉
Sorry, no way.
得三千蚊去边度买零件喎？
How can we buy spare parts with only $3,000?
我都苦冇良策架
There's nothing I can do.
鬼叫你的名字是弱者咩
The trouble is your name is frailty.
靓仔，入唔入会呀
Won't you join us?
入唔入，入唔入，入唔入会
Yes, yes.
入呀，入呀，入
入黎的佢上天台做大戏
Come in and take him to the roof to do an opera.
大佬
Buddy.
哎吔，话咗你唔好大佬、兄弟架喇
I told you not to call me buddy.
呢啲系黑社会唧背语黎架
It's underworld slang only.
唔识法律架，一日懵几次
They take the law into their own hands.
叫我做Big brother
And call me Big Brother.
Big brother，我哋即踢即阉
Big Brother, we'll castrate anyone who joins us.
收咁多Small brother有咩用呀？
There's no point in adopting small brothers.
我话你都懵唧，九七就快到喇
You're crazy, 1997 is approaching fast.
如果唔系迫住搵水，点移民呀？
Without money how can we emigrate?
我哋黑社会呀，都驶惊九七
We're members of the underworld, no worries.
唉，嗰班老而不呀，咪一样系黑社会
Those old fellows are members of the underworld as well.
边个唔顺超，“略”边个
But they destroy anyone who goes against them.
乱咁加条罪俾人，就屈到人仆街
They'll frame anyone for any crime.
说话就打横黎讲，“略”到成街尸骸
They talk black into white and kill many innocents.
又话冇死到人
Yet they say none have been killed.
唉，咪仲黑过我哋
Aren't they worse than us?
哦，咁呀，当第二个字头同佢讲数啰
Well, take it as bargaining over terms then.
人哋字头十亿人呀
There number is one billion.
我哋字头攞条毛同人讲呀，傻唧
What have we got? To talk with a hair, idiot?
咦，你睇吓
No, look.
五百蚊咋喎
500 dollars.
系呀，系呀，嫌贵呀
Right, right.
有得倾，入黎呀...
Make a counter offer if you prefer. Come in.
请
Please.
有客到
A guest.
若姐呀，下次再买咯
Yo, let's come back later.
好
Okay.
拜拜！
Bye-bye.
咩话，你两个混吉呀？
What, are you trying to make trouble?
入亲黎呢度，一定要买
Once inside you must buy.
买，买，买
Buy, buy, buy.
买喇嘛？手指模，听日攞五十万黎
Leave your thumbprint and bring $500,000 tomorrow.
吓？啱啱话五百，而家五十万
It said $500, why half a million now?
五百就系车头玻璃
$500 for the windscreen only,
成架车就要五十万
the car costs $500,000.
咁我哋边度黎五十万呀
How can we have half a million?
有几多呀？
How much have you got?
得三千
Only $3,000.
嗱，呢三千蚊
Well, we'll take this money as a visiting fee.
就当系参观费 唔驶你买车喇，走喇
You don't have to buy. Go now.
Big brother，唔踢埋佢两个？
Big Brother why don't you bring them in?
一个瘦到唔够一百磅
One weighs less than 100 pounds
一个矮到唔够五尺二
and the other's less than 5'2".
就算考差佬都唔要喇，何况我哋
Even the police station won't take them, let alone us.
话俾佢哋知，要打手指模
Tell them to leave thumbprints.
呢啲系佢哋自愿俾我哋唧参观费
They've voluntarily paid us this for the visit.
剥晒佢啲衫，揼佢出门口
Take off their clothes and throw them out.
走呀
Go now.
岂有此理，咁即系明屈啫
Outrageous. What a frame up.
要屈呀，都俾我屈呀，益啲外人
Why don't you let me frame you instead?
嗰班山贼好恶架
Those thugs are tough.
我呀，未见过恶人呀
I've never seen any tough guys in my life.
唔好咁冲动
Keep cool,
双拳难敌四手呀，周时劈
fists can't fight four hands.
咁点呀？吓，唔通算数呀？
What then? Are we to call it quits?
而家若姐都冇晒钱买零件喇
Now Yo has no more money for spare parts
我哋都应该搞弄架沟女车架
we should get a car to fool around with.
我有个老友有架van可以借住黎用唧
My friend's got a van, let's borrow it off him.
咁零件呢？
What about the spare parts?
唉，咁易喇，去街记执咪得啰
Let's try to get them from the market.
街记喺边度呀？
Where is it?
咪喺街嗰度啰
In the street.
半夜出去
Are we going out at midnight?
钟意边件，执边件番黎
Pick any piece you like.
吓，嗰四个死仔真系蛇王
Those four really are lazy,
咁早上铺
they've closed already.
Badman？
Bad Man.
坚叔，Badman车
Uncle Kin a Bad Man car.
Badman车？
A Bad Man car?
Badman车，加件Badman袍
A Bad Man car plus a Bad Man robe.
咁至有型呀
That's quite smart.
算你三个喇，今晚放早你哋十五分钟
Well I'll let you leave 15 minutes earlier tonight.
Badman袍
Bad Man robe.
妈咪，吸血僵尸呀
Mummy a vampire.
唔驶惊，唔驶惊呀
Don't be afraid, don't be afraid.
人哋话吸血僵尸呀
They say vampire.
拜！
Bye.
你架车好得意呀，俾我揸
Your car's funny, let me drive it.
你唔识揸架？
You can't.
你唔俾我揸，我唔理你架
Let me drive it or I won't listen to you.
好喇，怕你喇
Okay, you win.
文文呀，其实我觉得 你仲靓过你家姐
Man Man, I think you're more beautiful than your sister.
嗰日当你第一次踏入我车房门口呢
When you first stepped into the entrance of my garage,
我就知道你系上天送俾我唧安慰奖
I knew you were a consolation prize from heaven.
咪咁闷喇，开啲音乐听吓喇
Turn on the music, I'm so bored.
唔该你禁禁啲掣呀
Push the button please.
点解会咁唧？
What's going on?
可以解安全带嘞
You may unfasten your seatbelt.
你试吓嗰个掣呀，开啲音乐听吓呀
Try this, I want some music.
新马仔？咩事呀？
- Sun Ma Tsai. - Yes?
哎吔，好难听呀
It's so jarring.
哎，可以转台架
Switch to another station.
突破时刻，由杜里牧师主讲
Breakthrough hour compared by Rev. Dulles.
你们不可奸淫，奸淫的人有祸了
The one betide those who commit adultery.
都话咗唔好架喇，上帝闹架
Don't, god forbid.
任意妄为，你们必会后悔 偷情的人有祸了
Woe betide those who adulterate.
各位少女听住，唔好乱相信所谓爱情
Ladies, don't be misled by so-called love
就俾人欺骗，同埋乱发生关系
and don't get involved in sexual complications.
原来你昆我唧
So you're a love crook.
你咪听佢乱噏喇
Don't listen to this nonsense.
喂，唔好走喇
Hey, don't go away.
乱噏啫嘛
He's only muttering nonsense.
哎，咁都信唧
Don't believe in it.
最衰架车呀，拆咗佢
Damn that car, let's wreck it.
咁点算呀？
What now?
你唔驶惊呀，总要定
Keep calm.
听住，冚巴郎企度唔准郁
Listen, all of you freeze.
冇俾佢吓窒呀
Don't be threatened by them.
我哋拆咗你架车
We'll wreck your car.
仲黎
Don't. You're lucky,
算你哋好彩呀，我用塑胶子弹
I used plastic bullets.
如果好似人哋咁用真子弹，你哋死喇
Had I used real bullets like they did you'd have died.
我哋喺后边进攻佢
Let's attack from behind.
哗，臭过屎坑，喂
Oh, it's stinker than manure.
系唔系呀？话咗你班茄喱啡架喇
Well, I already warned you extras.
好躝尸歧路添，如果唔系有杀冇赔呀
Now get out or we'll kill you.
俾我禁下啲掣，试下得唔得呀？
Let me push the button to see if it works.
又黎喇，唔好乱禁呀，喂
Don't do it at random. Don't.
唔好呀，你真系唔得喱
No.
救命呀
Help!
好痛呀？
Does it hurt badly?
死喇你，死喇你
Damn you, damn you.
发明，发咩明呢
An invention? What invention?
哗，坚叔
Oh, uncle Kin.
哎吔，你真系俾人打到咁样呀？
You really got beaten up badly.
唉，早知我介绍你买呢种保险喇
I should have got you to take some insurance out.
咁而家有得赔喇
Then you'd be getting compensation now.
咩呀？
What?
因口臭或性骚扰或者样衰或无厘头
Insurance against assault arising from libel,
引致被人围殴保险
sexual harassment or bad looks.
只要你证明其中一瓣，有四分一赔
If only you can prove either one you'd get 25%.
哦，四瓣开齐发达喇
I'm lucky, I can prove all of them.
早排之嘛
Some time ago
陈百祥呀，喺澳洲俾人打
Chan Pai Cheung was assaulted in Australia
四瓣齐，赔足
and he got 100% compensation.
你介绍都有得赔？
Would I benefit by getting it through you as a go between?
咪喇，俾我出去抖抖先
Well let me go out for a rest.
喂，坚叔
Hello uncle Kin.
喂，我仲未发市呀，你帮我买多少吖
I've only just started. Buy some.
最多我帮你沟隔离啲女呀
In return I'll help you seduce that girl next door.
喂...系呀帮吓我哋呀
Hello. You can help us.
好
Okay.
买保险喇
Take out some insurance.
喂，听讲你系沟女专家
Is it true you're a love doctor?
都唔知坚定流喎？
Are you sure?
梗系坚喇
Sure.
嗱，一场朋友
As your friend,
而家我醒几招你哋叹吓先
let me show you something.
如果系啱用唧 就帮小弟买多少保险喇
If it works take out some insurance with me.
我哋听晚约咗隔离四个女仔去睇戏呀
We're taking the four girls from next door to a movie tomorrow night.
啱嘞，啱嘞，戏院沟女
Good, good, we can seduce them there.
系追女十三招唧基本入门法黎架
These are the rudimentary 13 ways to seduce a girl.
摆櫈
Arrange the chairs.
世界上，有好多种女人
There are girls and girls.
所以追女仔唧方法有好多种
There are many ways to seduce them.
你呀，过黎
Come here you.
哎，叫你去呀
He wants you to go over.
去呀
Go over.
黎喇，坐低呀
Come on, sit down.
有啲人，好似我咁，够勇，先来一招
Brave men like me do it this way.
大鹏展翅，搭实个膊头
Pat you hand on her shoulder.
然后啲攻势好似排山倒海咁
Then attack like an avalanche.
暴风雨一样，上下其手
Paw her all over like a hurricane.
得就得，唔得攞番三十蚊，散Band
You make it or part with $30 to get off the hook.
唉，呢招啱我喇
This suits me best.
喂，仲有冇第二招架？
What about the second way?
梗系有喇，你呢一种呀，至啱扮可怜
Sure, play small if it suits you best.
嗱，去到戏院时候呢，服侍佢坐好
Take her to her seat inside the cinema.
要扮Gentleman喎，剥咗件衫先
Take off your coat like a gentleman.
小姐呀，冷气好冻架，冚住佢先喇
Miss, it's cold in here, keep covered.
唔该
Thank you.
冚好呀
Not bad.
嗱，你记住呀，千祈唔好乱黎
Remember, don't play tough.
要等，耐心，一路等
Wait patiently till the show is over.
等到开场唧时候
Play it cool,
哗，嗰啲冷气好冻喇！扮冻
"the air-conditioning is so cold."
好冻呀，哎吔好冻呀
Oh, it's so cold.
哎吔好冻呀，冻到震添
"It's so cold I'm trembling."
震吓，震吓，震吓埋啲，震吓又埋啲
The more you shake the more you get closer.
哎吔，震吓埋啲...
The more you shake, the closer.
好冻呀，好冻呀...
It's so cold, so cold.
你女朋友见你震成咁样呀
Seeing you trembling with cold
都唔好意思叫你缩开只手喇，系咪先
she won't stop you, will she?
哎吔，震吓埋啲，震吓埋多啲
You get closer and closer
震吓，咁咪冻都变暖，搞弄
and then you get warm and it works.
呢一招叫斧底抽薪，明唔明？
This is called "dramatic." Understand?
唓，普通嘢黎啫
So-so
如果撞倒啲又恶又正
What if you should come upon a tough girl
又唔想同佢反面嗰啲女
and you want to cool her off?
你又有咩招数？
What have you got then?
识嘢呀
That's a good question.
好，就过招摸手踭你玩吓
Here's the trick of "touching the elbow."
摸手仔系有啫，手踭有乜好摸呵
What good is there in touching an elbow?
摸手踭？
Touching the elbow?
话咗你唔够班即系唔够班喇
As I said, you're not yet up to scratch.
摸手踭系战略重地黎架
The elbow is an important strategic position.
以为冇乜嘢，啲女仔唔会反感架
A girl won't resist this strongly.
嗱，听住喇，大家排排坐
Now, listen, you sit next to her
只手慢慢伸过去，摸吓个手踭
and stretch out her hand slowly to touch her elbow.
突然间，进可攻
Attack if the opportunity arises.
摸吓，摸吓，退可守
Touch, touch or retreat if need be.
可以明攻 可以暗攻
Attack openly or attack secretly.
唔钟意攻唧 摸吓手仔啰
If you don't attack just touch her hand.
或者反守为攻，攞番只手过隔离
Or attack by putting your hand on her other hand.
以为冇乜嘢，其实仲摸紧架
In fact you're still touching her.
千变万化呢
Be flexible.
哈，好嘢，不愧系追女专家
Great, you really are a love doctor.
系呀
Right.
系呀，不过大家至紧要记住
One thing you must remember is
九十年代女人唧心态，系好奇怪唧
that girls of the 90's have a strange mentality.
佢哋好想俾人追
They want to be seduced
又唔想俾人觉得咁易追到喎
but don't want to show they can be easily seduced.
所以，你哋就要低姿态啲
So take a low-key stance.
追到都要当追唔到
Make believe you're seducing her
着数咗呀，要当冇着数
when you've already won her heart.
咁佢哋咪有面啰
Make believe you've gained nothing.
咪锡到你哋燶晒，系咪先？
Then she'll keep her pride and love you from the bottom of her heart. Right?
吓，系嘛，Ok
Yes, okay.
呀，弄喇，记住咯喎
Good, remember it well.
嗱，帮衬小弟买番些小保险
Now take out some insurance with me
得唔得呀？
Okay?
得，不过你帮我哋做一件事
Yes, but do me a favour.
文文、德、贞、敏
Man Man, Tack Ching, Mun. Beautiful,
靓女，口水沾呢？
where's Bluffer Jim?
系Toilet呀，做咩呀？
In the toilet. What for?
呵，咁最好喇
So much the better.
喂，我帮隔离嗰四个男仔
I'm bringing you tickets
送飞黎俾你哋呀
from those boys next door.
因住俾老豆听到呀，喂，攞黎呀
Don't let daddy hear you. Show me.
嗱，飞后便呢 就写明系边度等你哋架喇
Look on the back and it tells you where to meet.
喂
Hello.
点解冇厕纸架？
Why no toilet paper?
唉，沾哥
Oh, Jim.
唉吔，沾哥，好耐冇见喇
Jim it has been a long time.
喂...咪喇
Hello, uh.
又想作我姨仔，定系我啲女呀？
Are you after my sister-in-law or my daughters?
我有啲嘢同你讲，好紧要
I have something important to talk to you about.
唉，入黎先喇
Do come in.
喂...做乜鬼呀？
Hey, what is he up to?
唔知呀
No idea.
唉，你知唔知咩系边缘人？
You know what a brinkman is?
知，戏都有得做喇
I saw him in a show.
我就系边缘人
I'm a brinkman.
你唔好以为隔离个刘定坚咁简单
Oh. Your neighbor Lau Ting Kin
佢系黑社会头子
is none other than an underworld boss.
吓，我都到吓喇
I imagined that.
我呀，就喺佢嗰度做卧底
I'm an undercover agent.
最近佢开始怀疑我，我咪为有走喇
Recently he was getting suspicious so I had to quit.
佢啲手段好残忍架
He's cold blooded.
你咪以为新黎嗰四个高矮肥瘦好简单
Those 4 boys of different sizes are killers.
系Killer黎架 最近连差佬都對冧埋呀
They even finished off some cops.
仲有呀
Besides this,
系越南营杀死差佬都系佢哋呀
they killed cops at the Vietnamese refugee camp too.
哦，系呀，变态架，仲装我冲凉呀
He's perverted. He peeped in when I was taking a bath.
系呀哩
He sure is.
早排啲鸡奸案呀，都怀疑系佢哋做架
They're suspected of being involved in sodomy cases.
咁我点算好呀？
What shall I do then?
唉，你唔驶惊
Don't worry.
只要你愿意同警方合作
If you cooperate with the police.
假意对佢哋好啲，即系帮我吸住佢
Pretend to be nice to them.
如果佢哋约啲女去街呢
If they date your daughters
就俾佢哋去，以免引起怀疑喇嘛
let them go out with them to avoid suspicion.
嗱，睇住刘定坚
Remember, watch Lau Ting Kin.
有咩事，Call我喇
Call me if anything happens.
哗，咁我处境咪好危险，呀？
I'm in a dangerous situation then?
你嫌危险呀，好，我搵第二个人做
Well, I'll find someone else.
不过，边个捉到刘定坚有一百万暗花
There's a million dollars for the arrest of Lau Ting Kin.
我系好市民黎架
I'm a model citizen.
呢啲嘢除咗我之外，冇人啱做架喇
No one can do the job better than me.
喺呢度
Here it is.
姐夫呀，咩事呀？
Brother-in-law what happened?
呀，冇嘢，冇嘢，呀，系呀
Nothing, nothing.
第日如果隔离嗰几个男仔约你哋去街
Well, if the boys next door date you
系咁意去吓喇，唔好推得咁绝喎，吓
don't turn them down.
记住呀
Remember.
Hi
Hi.
吓，乜系你呀
Oh, it's you.
系啰，我哋不如入场咯
We'd better go in.
入场？好，行喇
Go in? Okay.
唔该俾包鱿鱼丝，同埋一包牛肉干呀
One packet each of cuttle fish and dried beef please.
好呀
Okay.
乜系你呀？
Oh, it's you.
系呀，而家好失礼你咩？
Sure, am I a disgrace to you?
唔系
I don't mean that.
望咩呀？
What are you staring at?
杀咗你全家，放火烧埋你间屋
I'll kill your whole family, set fire to your house.
爆谷呀，唔该
Popcorn please.
我哋，我哋入场啰
Let's go in.
好呀，买啲嘢食呀
Okay, buy something to eat.
喂，整包爆谷黎，大包啲呀
Hey, one whole bag of popcorn, bigger.
算你喇
Well, I forgive you.
我哋入场咯，请跟我黎
Let's go in, please follow me.
未够十八岁喎？
Not yet up to 18 years of age?
我买飞架喎
I've got a ticket.
冇得倾呀，走喇
Sorry, go now.
攞身分证睇吓
Show me your ID card.
咩呀？
What?
呢套三级片黎架
People under the age of 18
未够十八岁唔准入场架
are not allowed to see this category three movie.
我廿八岁架喇
I'm already 28.
攞身分证黎睇吓先喇
Show me your ID card.
真系唔记得带喎
I forgot to bring it.
番屋企攞喇，唔系就冇得入架
Go home and get it or you'll be barred.
我真的廿几岁架喇
I really am 28 years old.
哎，你话俾佢听我几多岁呀
Tell him how old I am.
十六呀
Sixteen.
咁你入场先喇，我番去攞
You go in now, I'll go home to get it.
乜系你，敏敏呢？
Oh, it's you. Where's Mun Mun?
哦，你约咗敏敏呀，咁我走喇
I dated Mun Mun, I must leave.
我约你
I've dated you.
睇埋晒啲咁唧恐怖片，你都奸呀
You're crafty, you've brought me to a horror picture.
行喇，一碌木咁      哦
- Don't just stand there let's get going. - Yes.
唔该
Excuse me.
Hi，黎，坐
Hi, come and sit down.
乜系你呀，朱玉干
Oh it's you Dried Pork.
系你呀
It's you.
进可攻，退可守...
Advance or retreat?
咩呀？
What?
立体电影黎架
It's a 3-D movie.
啲拳头呀兜口兜面打埋黎架
The fists come right to your face.
黎，戴眼镜先喇，吓
Put these glasses on first.
进可攻，退可守...
Advance or retreat?
睇戏
Keep your eyes on the screen.
你冻唔冻呀？
Are you cold?
我除衫俾你冚呀
Let me take off my coat to cover you up.
唔冻呀，留番你喇
No, keep it for yourself.
咦，斧底抽薪唔弄喎 唔系喇，整招大鹏展翅先
Oh it doesn't work. Let me try the other trick.
人人一条女，你嗰唔摸，摸我嗰条
One girl every day, don't touch my girl.
我追咗佢三年
I've seduced her for 3 years
大髀都未摸过，你截我糊
but have never touched her leg. Now you've stolen a march.
唔觉意，唔觉意呀
Sorry, sorry.
下次唔好呀
Next time don't do it.
我都知你咸架嘞 不过唔知你咸成咁啫
I knew you'd cry but not the way you do.
你睇人哋呀，咸得几有型呀
Look, she's crying with such good presentation.
边度好似你咁衰吖
Not as bad as you did.
你唔好话识得我添呀
Pretend not to know me,
唔该你坐嗰度呀
sit over there please.
一个人过去坐我惊架
I'm scared to sit alone.
咁你唔坐我坐喇吓
I'll take the seat then.
我...我坐
I will.
俾我知道系边个导演拍唧呢
If I knew who'd directed this movie
我劈开佢九十几碌
I'd chop him into 90 pieces.
你睇吓，个个都做到冇晒瘾唧
Look, everyone's working like hell.
都唔知识唔识拍戏架，你睇吓
He must be new to directing,
个个都黑口黑面架
look everyone's wearing a stony face.
嗰度全部都黑人黎架喎
They're all black men.
唔该细声啲呀
Hush.
殊，殊你亚妈个蟹呀
Damn you,
唔好睇就嘘嘛，多事
I booed it because it's disgusting, damn you.
点解，点解咁耐都冇床上戏唧
Why?
又唔剥衫唧
Why no bedroom scene and no stripping?
嗰啲修女黎架嘛
She's a nun.
难道修女不洗澡吗？
Does a nun have to take a bath?
老友呢度唔准食烟架喎
No smoking here pal.
你边只眼睇见我食烟呀？
Which of your eyes saw me smoking?
呢只呀
This one.
仆你个臭街喇
To hell with you.
仲睇唔睇到呀？
You can't see it now can you?
睇唔到喇...
No.
睇唔到喇嘛
Can't see it now.
头先嗰句讲紧咩呀？
What was that line?
我咩都唔知呀，咩都睇唔到呀
I don't know, I don't know.
如果俾我知道系边个导演拍唧呢
If I knew who the director was
我劈个冚家铲
I'd chop that bastard.
嗰个系法国导演黎架喎
He's a French director.
佢死咗好耐架喇
He died a long time ago.
哦，死咗好耐
I see.
梗系俾我法国啲兄弟對冧佢喇
My brothers in France must've finished him off.
喂，老友呀
Hey pal, quiet please.
你俾我静静地睇下戏得唔得呀 哎吔，第二个你唔管
Why don't you shout at someone else?
吓，你好钟意望我呀？
Do you enjoy staring at me?
好，罚你唔准睇戏，成晚望住我
Don't watch it anymore as punishment.
唔准望第二度，揸耳仔
Don't look anywhere else. Grab your ears.
进可攻，退可守...
Advance or retreat?
知唔知我以前喺边度做嘢架？
Don't you know what I did before?
牛奶公司呀，明攻，暗攻
Dairy farm. Open attack, secret attack.
喂，身分证呀
Hello, ID card.
原来你够十八岁架嗱
So you're already 18.
够呀
Yes.
做咩啫？黐线架你
- What's up? - Are out of your mind?
香港政府几时话过
Does the HK government say
有身分证就可以睇戏架
anyone with an ID card can see movies?
飞呢？
Tickets?
唉，跌咗
Dropped.
吖，唔怕，我去补飞呀
Don't worry, I'll buy another one.
哎吔，死喇
Oh no. What about me?
咁我点呀？你头先明明见到我有飞架
You saw me holding a ticket just now.
我女朋友喺里面睇紧戏架
My girlfriend is watching the movie inside.
呢啲嘢要我经理先揸得主意个噃
Only our manager can decide on this.
咁你经理喺边呀？
Where's your manager?
啱啱去咗厕所喇
In the toilet.
经理呀，经理
Manager, manager?
咩事呀？
Yes.
你唔好疴住呀，你卖张飞俾我先喇
Wait, give me a ticket first.
唔得呀，肚疴呀
I can't, I have an internal disorder.
你唔好去住喇，卖张飞俾我先喇
Give me a ticket first.
你等我疴完先卖俾你喇
Wait till I've finished.
唔好哩，你卖张飞俾我先喇
No, sell me a ticket first.
你睇咩戏咩紧要呀？
What kind of show is it?
“红豆沙情人”第廿九集呀
Red Bean Puree Lovers part 29.
嗰套戏唔好睇架
It's not a good film,
唔得，唔得，我入去喇
I must go in.
唔好呀，你唔好疴住
Don't,
你卖张飞俾我先喇
sell me a ticket first.
我都话啲三级片毒害青少年架喇
Category 3 films like this poison youngsters.
你睇到Shock咗呀
You may lose your mind watching it.
我疴完送张飞俾你呀
I'll give you a ticket after I finish.
唔得呀，你疴完散场架喇
No, the show will be over then,
我唔俾得你疴架
don't go.
唔得呀，出黎呀，出番黎呀...
No, I can't hold on anymore.
我求下你卖张飞俾我喇
I beg you to sell me a ticket.
你哋以后呀，都唔准睇咁闷唧戏
I Don't watch such a boring show anymore.
要睇，睇黄晶唧戏，知唔知？
If you want, watch a Wong Jim show. Understand?
咪行住
Hold it.
同阿姐讲声，我走喇
Say goodbye to me.
阿姐，我走喇
Goodbye.
喂，醒你的
Hey, come here.
你睇吓，我哋几有Face呀，系唔系
Look we've got allot of face right?
系
Yes.
入得场喇...
We may go in.
散咗场喇，小朋友
The show's over little friend.
等埋佢哋先一齐走喇，好唔好？
Wait for them okay.
你同边个一齐黎睇架？
Who were you seeing the film with?
咪同嗰个罗家铃啰
Lo Kar Ling.
点呀？
What happened?
喂，佢做咩嘢呀？
What did she do?
咪俾嗰套戏吓成咁架咯
She was really scared by the film.
嗱，你家姐咪喺度
Well, your sister's are here.
家姐呀，我哋走喇
Sisters let's go.
喂，去庙街宵夜，我请
Hey, let's have snacks at Temple Street,
唔驶客气喇
I'll pay.
喂，你哋入去睇下你哋唧朋友喇
Don't be so formal. Go in and see your friend.
朋友
Friend.
朱玉干呀
Dried Pork.
喂，朱玉干，散场喇
Hey Dried Pork it's over.
朱玉干，你冇事嘛？
Dried Pork are you alright?
喂，咩事呀？乜套戏咁短唧
Hey, what's wrong. Why was the show so long?
一开场就散场
The moment it started it ended.
一捶打到我晕咗喎
One punch knocked me unconscious.
喂，以后唔好预我喇
Next time don't count me in.
得喇，得喇
Okay, okay.
唉，有乜好唉呀
Why are you sighing?
而家天安门嗰便都知你四个失恋喇
Now Tianamen knows you are frustrated in love.
唉！
Oh.
一日都系刘备喇
It was all the fault of Lau Pei.
调转晒啲飞，搞到错点鸳鸯
He mixed up all the tickets.
正衰人黎架
He's damned.
我送啲保险黎架
I'm bringing you the insurance policies.
保你个咸水草呀
Damn you.
我未斩你呀
I should have chopped you.
我知道你哋搞到一镬粥咁
I know you've been in a mess.
今日我黎呀，系通风报讯
I'm here to bring you some news.
咩呀？
What is it?
隔离黑记车房呀
The people from Darkie Garage opposite
成班人围住口水沾间铺呀
are surrounding Bluffer Jim's shop.
你间车行影响我黑记车行唧生意
Your garage affects our business.
我而家情商你改行
I'm persuading you to change your business
免致争生意
to avoid unnecessary competition.
即系靠吓啫
That sounds like a threat.
话咗情商架喇
We can talk it over.
呢个世界讲民主、自由架嘛
We're all for democracy and freedom.
河水不犯井水
We won't interfere in each others business.
以后你间铺头火烛、冧楼
As of now anything that happens to you, fire,
架车撞入黎，啲客俾人打
car crash, assault,
半夜起身满地都系蛇
burglary,
爆屎渠爆到入屋
burst water pipes etc,
呢啲全部都唔关我事架
these are none of my business.
我本来唔想暴露身分唧
I didn't want to expose my identity,
而家冇法啦
but now I must.
我就系香港皇家警察
I am a Royal Hong Kong Policeman
特派黎监视黑社会头子唧边缘人喇
and a brinkman assigned to watch gang bosses.
边缘人？
Brinkman?
老豆，乜你系边缘人呀？
Daddy what's a brinkman?
Big brother，佢抛你都唔定喎
Big Brother it could be a hoax.
抛吓就无所谓呀，至怕系坚架啫
I wish it wasn't true.
我哋过去隔离盘吓个刘定坚
Let's go over to ask Lau Ting Kin.
系咩大佬，咁咪知啰
Good, Big Brother.
唔，叻仔
You're smart.
失敬，失敬，去饮杯奶茶先喇
Thank you, let's have some tea first.
惊呀哩？走迟半步呀擝炮啡你添呀
Scared, if you had left any later I would have shot you.
喂，喂，企系度，一个都唔准去
Hey, stand there. None of you shall leave.
口水沾啲人都好帮唧
Don't take sides with Bluffer Jim.
横弄冇嘢做之嘛
Anyway we have nothing to do.
咩冇嘢做呀？嗱，俾啲嘢你做
Nothing? I'll give you some work to do.
我对鞋烂咗，你帮我黐番佢
My shoes are torn, glue them for me.
你呀，房仔把风扇坏咗 即刻整番好佢
And you fix that fan in the room.
仲有你呀
And you,
厕所有只老鼠，攞碌棍去扑湿佢
get a pole to hit that rat in the toilet.
行呀
Okay.
喂，你唔好以为系大哥
Pretend to be a Big Brother.
下个轮到你架喇
Next time it will be your turn.
冇所谓
I don't mind.
哎吔，杀到黎喇
Oh, here he is.
边个系刘定坚呀？
Who's Lau Ting Kin?
佢呀
It's him.
咩料呀？边个搵我老顶呀？
What's up? Who's looking for my boss?
上喇
Come on.
有料喎，盘盘佢
Well question him.
喂，呢处冇职员呀？
Hello, any staff here?
一眼睇晒喇
See for yourself.
咦，棍扇鞋黎咗喎
Oh, Kun Sin Hai is here.
Big brother，考吓佢诗句
Big Brother test out his poems.
哎吔，唔菺喇
It won't work...
九十九楼睇烟花
Watch fireworks from the 99th floor
唔见咗个大冬瓜
and lose a big melon.
和气生财大家好
Peace benefits everybody.
唔要你老豆就要你呀妈
I want you mommy if not your daddy.
请指教，指教
Please enlighten me.
唉，罗家铃，你搅弄佢
Lo Kar Ling you fix him.
朱玉干读书多过我喎，叫佢搞弄佢喇
Dried Pork is more educated, you let him solve it.
呀，系喎，系喎
Right, right.
去喇，去，去喇嘛
Go on, go on.
睇戏要睇周润发
To see a show, see Chow Yun Fat.
戴表请戴英纳格
To wear a watch wear Enigar.
见到曱甴用喷即杀，喷完饮杯嘉士伯
Use insecticide spray for cockroach and drink Carlsberg.
死喇你，叫你卖广告咩
Damn you your advertising.
哦，原来冇料到唧
So, he's good for nothing.
又话咩边缘人，咩大佬辈
And he claims to be a brinkman, a big brother.
唉，叫啲手足拆咗隔离间铺先
Get the men to pull down that shop opposite.
系
Yes.
我哋拆咗呢间
Let's pull this down.
好
Okay.
边个敢郁手
Who dares do it?
我呀，点吖？
What now?
冇，想得个知字啫
I only want to know why.
大佬呀，唔好郁手住，你想点你讲喇
Big Brother don't, just say what you want.
唔好叫我大佬呀，费事暴露我身分
Don't call me Big Brother to expose myself.
由听日开始，唔准做车行
As of tomorrow don't be in the garage business.
做乜嘢都得
You can do anything else.
如果唔系同你拆档架
Otherwise I'll pull your shop down.
嗱，听日呀
If I see you in the garage business tomorrow
再见你哋开车行呢，冇面俾架
I'll turn nasty.
走！
Let's go.
咩呀？扮边缘人
What? To play a brinkman?
呢个死人口水沾，仲睇唔到你仆街
Damn Bluffer Jim, you're finished once and for all.
老豆，你点呀？
Daddy, what now?
你哋仲笑，一日都系你哋呀
Don't laugh, it was all your fault.
呃老头话咩边缘人
You lied to me about being a brinkman.
我憎死你哋呀
I hate your guys.
我哋唔好睬佢哋啫，我哋走啰
Never mind them, let's go.
老豆你点呀？
Daddy, are you alright?
坚叔呀，咁我哋点呀？
Uncle Kin what shall we do?
有乜点啫，最多咪转行
At worst we'll switch to another business.
横弄都冇生意做咯
Anyhow we have no business now.
转行做咩啫？
What line of business?
哎，我介绍你哋转行
I'll make you a recommendation.
我知道最近有一间海鲜火锅
I know a sea food hot pot restaurant
佢哋执咗笠
that is closing down.
我哋顶晒佢啲架撑 喺度开番间咁咪弄啰
Let's take over their business and run it.
得，得，嗱，做咩都得
Okay, okay, anything will do.
不过，你哋记住，限你三百蚊搞弄
But remember it will have to be set up with $300 only.
嗱
Here you are.
喂，做乜呀？四只死嘢冚巴郎唔做嘢
What's wrong? Why are all of you being idle?
都冇客，边有嘢做喎
There's no customers.
今日隔离开张大吉
The shop next door is opening today
门庭若市，生意兴隆
and doing a roaring business.
欢迎，欢迎呀
Welcome, welcome.
各位，各位街坊，欢迎，各位黎帮衬
Ladies and gentlemen thank you for coming.
今日沾沾烧鸡鸭店开张
Today's the opening of Jim Jim barbecue poultry.
凡系帮衬唧小朋友，都有礼物送
Free gifts for any children.
点呀？刘定坚，冇生意呀？
Well, Lau Ting Kin, no business?
执咗佢过黎同我打工喇
Close your shop and work for me.
我俾番八蚊一个钟你哋
I'll pay you $8 an hour,
好过麦当劳架
better than McDonald's.
边个咁有钱俾你装修成咁唧样架
Who financed your beautiful decorations?
乜钱都系问题咩？
Money is no problem.
关公子打本俾我
Mr. Kwan gave me the capital,
而家佢系我Partner
he's now my partner.
刘定坚，你间铺仲有三个月就满约
Lau Ting Kin your lease expires in 3 months.
到时我决定加你二十倍租
I'll increase your rent 20 times then.
岂有此理，扮鸡扮鸭
Outrageous, he's got chicken and duck costumes.
食嘢送气球，咁就咁多人入去啰喎
Free balloons and this attracts business.
喂...佢哋买鸡鸭就扮鸡鸭
Hey, they're dressed as chickens and ducks to sell chickens and ducks.
我哋买海鲜就扮Seafood
Let's dress as seafood to sell seafood.
死吖你
Damn it.
各位街坊，入黎随便坐喇喂
Ladies and gentlemen come in please.
好靓啊，坚记海鲜火锅店，入黎
Kin Ke's seafood hot pot restaurant's fine.
各位街坊，欢迎...随便入黎坐吓
Ladies and gentlemen you're welcome.
喂，黎帮衬吓喇
Hello, come in to eat.
唏...坚记火锅系最好呢
Hi, Kin Ke's hot pot is the best.
唏，唏，唏
Hi, hi, hi.
蚌精香艳又迷人呢
Miss Oyster is glamorous and bewitching.
唏，唏，唏
Hi, hi, hi.
食完仲有洋楼送呀 系人都送十万银呢
Free flats and $100,000 gifts.
做咩打我？
Why are you hitting me?
傻架你呀？
Are you crazy?
无端端做咩每人送十万银啫？
$100,000 for everyone?
做乜送十万银吓
Why?
横弄点人，咪点得劲啲啰
Let's count the number generously.
系啰，系啰
Right, right.
咁又系噃
Right.
每人都送十万银呢
$100,000 for everyone.
喂，喂，冇汤，喂
Hey, hey, hey. No soup, hey.
攞汤黎
Bring the soup.
快啲攞黎呀
Hurry up.
喂，又话有蚌精出现架，点解冇架？
Hey didn't you say there would be a Miss Oyster?
蚌精呢？吓
Where is she?
各位街坊，蚌精呢准备紧 好快出场喇
She's putting on her makeup and will be here soon.
大家食住火锅先喇，好快，好快呀
Eat the hot pot first. It won't be long.
唔弄呀，蚌精唔肯出场，佢要加价呀
No way, she won't appear. She wants to raise the price.
快叫坚叔喇，快啲喇，去呀
Call for uncle Kin at once.
喂，姐姐，你做乜扭计呀？
Hey sister why are you being so naughty?
哎吔，你都冇同我讲出便咁多麻甩佬
You didn't tell me there'd be so many men out there.
我咁样出去呀，容乜易溶咗我
They may swallow me if I go out.
咁危险，加三千喇
Pay me $3,000 more
咩话？加三千蚊
and I'll go out for this special appearance.
三千蚊你杀咗我好过
What? You'd better kill me?
蚌精出场
Introducing Miss Oyster.
蚌精，蚌精，蚌精
Miss Oyster, Miss Oyster, Miss Oyster.
各位街坊呀，系蚌精表演之前呢
Ladies and gentlemen before her performance
我哋先抽出一位幸运现场朋友先
let's draw a lucky member from the audience.
佢就系... 姚小雄
He is Yiu Siu Hung.
嗱，姚生，只要你转我哋嗰个幸运轮
Mr. Yuan,
转到哩格唧话呢
only by turning our lucky wheel to this section
你就得到洋楼一层喇
will you get a flat.
洋楼，洋楼，洋楼
A flat, a flat, a flat.
过啲，过啲，过啲
Over, over, over.
我哋恭喜姚小雄先生有洋...
Congratulations to Mr. Yiu Siu Hung on winning...
葱一个
an onion.
有冇搞错呀？
What's wrong?
洋葱呀      唔紧要
- The onion. - Never mind.
只要回答一条简单唧问题
Only if you answer a simple question correctly
就可以得到我哋唧特别奖
you will get our special prize,
就系由蚌精陪同，去九龙塘Soft一宵
that is to spend one night with Miss Oyster in Kowloon Tong
共度周末
for the weekend.
好嘢呀
Great.
好简单呀，唔好紧张呀
It's simple, take it easy.
最近有个开咗卅八场演唱会唧歌星
Which singer has recently held 38 concert shows?
谭咏麟
Alan Tam.
唧老豆
His father Tam Pak Wong.
谭伯江 未问完，唧二表叔
Not yet finished, his uncle Tam Shing King.
谭上颈
Not yet,
未问完嗱 个契伯娘个三婶个侄孙个叔婆
an auntie's, auntie's grandnephew's grandauntie's auntie's cousin's son.
个契姨个表姐个仔系边个？
Who is it?
俾Tips呀
Tips, tips please.
唔系梅艳芳
Not Anita Mui.
答唔到黎
You can't answer it.
谭咏麟
Alan Tam.
咁难谂都俾佢谂到唧
He's real smart to have answered it.
唔系我谂倒架
I'm not,
反转张纸我睇到架咋
I turned over the paper and saw what was written on it.
蚌精，蚌精，蚌精
Miss Oyster, Miss Oyster, Miss Oyster.
望咩？我架
Don't stare, it's mine.
请保持冷静...
Please keep calm, keep calm.
搵笨唧
It's a set up.
俾钱呀...喂
Pay up, hey.
喂，食霸王嘢呀？
Hey, trying to sponge?
喂，俾钱呀
Hey, pay up.
快啲俾钱呀
Pay up now.
咩呀？发瘟鸡
What is it creep?
刘定坚你点够我斗呀，执笠喇
You can't compete with me Lau Ting Kin, close down.
哈，你个死嘢你吖
Damn you bastard,
信唔信我钳死你吖
bet I kill you.
我驶怕你的臭虾臭蟹
I'm not afraid of your stinking shrimps and crab.
鱼、虾、蟹，买喇，买喇
Fish, shrimps, crabs, bet, bet.
开，开蟹
It's crab.
开蟹，通杀
Crab, banker takes all.
开，开鸡，又杀，赔一家
Chicken, banker takes again, pays one.
喂，你哋唔好再打喇
Hey, stop that.
坚叔，坚叔呀，嗰边开紧鱼虾蟹
Uncle Kin, there's a game over there.
我而家买虾，你瞓低
I'll bet on crab,
我预你三千蚊呀
I've $3,000 ready.
买喇，买喇...
Bet, bet.
五千蚊买虾
$5,000 on shrimp.
中虾
Medium shrimp.
差...差佬黎呀，走鬼呀
Cops, cops, let's run.
喂，乜你哋咁野蛮架？
Hey, why are you getting out of hand?
咩啫，咁佢哋唔野蛮咩？
They're even more unruly.
我唔理咁多
I don't care.
总之我哋以后就冇朋友做
Anyway it's over between us.
衰人
Creep.
番入去啰
Go back in.
呀，唔记得买梘粉添
Oh, I forgot the detergent.
得力素呀，得力素呀
Deraxol, Deraxol.
细路仔饮架，你仲细咩
It's for chicken only,
无厘醒目架你
not for you.
Sorry呀
Sorry.
又会有四个野蛮人喺度唧
All four villains are here.
我哋运路行啰，行喇
Let's get out of here.
喂，佢哋走啰喎，咁我哋点啫
They're leaving now. What shall we do?
不如搵个人去讲句好说话吖
Get someone to say something nice.
唉，啱听
Good idea.
我唔弄架
I can't do it.
叉死你
I'll stab you.
你可唔可以唔咁无聊啫？
Don't be such a bore.
我唔系无聊架
I'm not a bore.
我系认真架
I'm serious.
我系好钟意你架
I'm fond of you.
钟意你个头呀
Shit!
咁我钟意你个身多啲喇
I love your body allot.
细佬，唔好恰我个妹喎
Buddy, don't bully my sister.
高妹，佢系甩你个妹，唔系恰你个妹
Tall sister he's jilting your sister.
你够姜出去倾弄佢
Talk it over if you have the nerve.
惊你打我呀！打女人唧男人冇用架
Who cares? A man using violence is no good.
啱听，女人系攞黎锡，唔系攞黎打唧
Right, a girl should be kissed, not beaten.
倾弄佢喇
Let's talk it over.
行喇，行呀
Go away, go away.
做乜啫
What's up?
唔好做电灯胆喇
Don't be a stumbling block.
通气吖嘛
Be smart.
其实佢哋三个咪同我一样
They all want too seduce you like I do.
想追你哋之嘛
...
钟意人冇罪架
Love is not a crime.
咁你又帮刘定坚打我老豆
Why did you help Lau to beat my daddy?
最多我以后两个都唔帮吖
Well, I won't take sides from now on.
咩呀？
What?
我谂办法等佢哋两个和好如初吖
I'll try to make them reconcile.
嗱，系至好呀
Are you sure?
哗，做咩呀？
Oh, what's wrong?
有得饮呀？
Going to a party?
我哋约咗四个靓女今晚去Disco
We're going to a disco with four girls tonight.
参加劲舞比赛呀
We're taking part in a hot dancing contest.
咁恭喜晒喇
Congratulations.
嗱，一场朋友醒啲嘢俾你哋
Well for old times sake let me show you something good.
英俊佬男士美容中心八折卡一张
A discount card for a male beauty parlour.
嗱，一人一张，唔好争喇
One for each man,
嗱，揸住呀
keep it.
哗，乜你成日跳出跳入唧啫
Why are you always jump in and out?
哗做咩？
What are you doing?
着到咁靓，做男妓呀？
Why are you dancing to and for dressed up as gigolos?
哦，冇，佢哋约咗四个女仔去Disco
They're going to a disco with four girls.
吖，你四个死仔，梗系飞起我
You creeps, you were counting me out.
冇法子喇，又唔够你靓仔
No way, we're not as smart as you are.
算你哋有自知之明喇
You're modest.
嗱，话你听呀，今晚大家齐去
Let's go together tonight.
除非我沟到其他啲女
I'll seduce all your girls
如果唔系沟晒你哋啲女
unless I have another one.
唔系吖嘛，咁都有唧
How come?
多谢晒你哋几位
Thank you very much gentlemen.
对我哋美容中心唧服务满唔满意呢？
Are you satisfied with our service?
满意，好满意
Yes, very much.
满意，非常满意
我哋美容中心呢
As a token of thanks
为咗多谢几位光临呢 除咗八折之外，仲有嘢送
we offer 20% off and free gifts too.
喂，送乜都得呀
Well,
千祈唔好送收缩水呀
don't ever give us the shrinking mixture.
试过一镬，我真系唔弄呀
I tried it before and felt the pinch.
梗系唔系收缩水喇，系青春丸呀
No, it's rejuvenation pills.
有咩好？
What're they for?
食咗一粒呀，就去啲皱纹喇
One pill removes wrinkles.
后生咗五年喇，啲皮肤呀，滑滑架
Your skin will look feel tender and you'll look five years younger.
咁多谢晒喎，我帮你俾佢哋呀
Thank you, let me give it to them for you.
收埋先
Let's put it aside.
先生，你休息一阵先喇
Take a rest sir.
咦，朱玉干，你饮咩呀？
Dried Pork what were you drinking?
吓，咩料呀？
What's the matter?
先生，你冇事吖嘛？
Are you alright sir?
哎吔，弊喇，坚叔，你睇吓
Oh no uncle Kin, look.
死嘞，我盲咗呀
Oh, I'm blind.
坚叔
Uncle Kin.
一个盲咗、一个哑咗，唔得
One's blind and the other's dumb.
喂，你冇事吖嘛
Hey, are you alright?
吓，请我食叉烧包
Give me a barbecue pork bun please.
咩，叉烧包呀？
What? Barbecue pork bun?
我听唔到自己讲嘢唧
What did you say?
你聋咗呀？
Are you dumb?
吓...
Alas.
咁死嘞，一个盲、一个聋、一个哑
Oh no, one's blind, one's dumb and one's mute.
咁我哋今晚点算好呀
What shall we do then?
仆街
Damn it.
帝女花带泪上香
In tears the princess offers to the shrine.
先生，饮乜呀？
What would you like to drink sir?
吓？
Alas!
饮咩呀？
What would you drink?
Cheers
Cheers.
死人刘定坚咁耐都未黎
Damn it, why's Lau Ting Kin still not here?
我实劈佢个冚家铲
I'll chop him dead.
大表哥呀，呢位小姐同你点火呀
Cousin she's lighting your cigarette for you.
唔系呀
No.
做咩呀你？
What are you doing?
唔系呀，佢想同你榨杯奶饮之嘛
He wants a glass of milk from you.
去你阿妈度攞喇
Go and get it from your mummy.
二表哥呀
Cousin.
你死人都要扮Cool呀
Play it cool come what may.
如果讲嘢，我同你唱双璜
If you talk I'll talk as well.
大表哥呀
Cousin,
你千祈唔好四围走呀
don't run around.
哦
Okay.
三表哥
Oh cousin.
哦！得喇用手语提醒我喇
Just remind me with hand signals.
你上咗身嗱
Are you possessed?
上你个头呀，我黎参加跳舞比赛呀
Nonsense, I'm taking part in the dancing competition.
如果赢咗啲奖金成万银架
I might win thousands in prizes.
我去厕所扮靓先
I go to toilet first.
刘定坚仆街喇你
Damn you, bloody Lau Ting Kin.
条女几正架喎
She's beautiful.
对唔住喎，亚伯
Sorry uncle.
呢个亚伯，好有型喎
This old man's quite presentable.
系呀
Yes.
亚伯？边度有亚伯？
Uncle? Who's uncle?
唔通我真系老得咁紧要
Am I looking so old?
好彩攞埋佢哋啲啫
Luckily I've taken away theirs too.
整几粒先
Let me take a few pills.
哈，黎喇，黎喇
Ha, they're coming.
Hi
Hi.
呢边呀
Over there.
Hi
Hi.
喂，周时劈，啲歌咁劲
Chou Sze Pok let's dance,
不如出去跳舞喇
the music's hot.
张櫈都未坐庆，等阵先喇
I only just got here, maybe later.
我今日好开心呀
I'm in the mood now.
你今日好开心
You're in the mood.
我同朋友行街
I went out with a friend,
经过长沙湾诗歌舞街中间条横巷
passed through a lane at the junction of Kormu Street,
有间专卖唱片唧Cassette档
saw a cassette stand
搵到饼徐柳仙唧“再折长亭柳”
and bought Hsu Lau Sin's Pavilion Willow.
全新录音，水准好高架
It was newly recorded and of a high standard.
你有冇唱子喉呀
Have you got a good voice?
我借俾你，你教我唱吖
Teach me how to sing.
我食咗饭，我食咗饭喇
I've already eaten, I've already eaten.
点解好似鸡同鸭讲咁架
We don't seem to be speaking the same language.
何家公鸡何家猜，何家母鸡何家猜
Whose cock is it? Whose hen is it?
唔系呀
Oh no.
喂，做咩啫？出去跳舞喇
What's wrong? Come and dance.
行喇
Come on.
喂，一阵间跳完舞去边呀？
Hey, where shall we go after dancing?
做乜成日粒声都唔出啫，你扮Cool呀
Why are you so quiet? Playing cool?
好呀，扮Cool呀，你继续扮喇
Well go on, go on.
一于系咁话咯喎
It's fixed,
借你男朋友黎驶吓
may I borrow your boyfriend.
行喇
Let's go.
去边呀？
Where to?
你激嬲咗人哋喇
You've offended her,
仲唔快啲追佢番黎，行喇
go and say sorry.
黎喇，快啲氹番佢喇，去喇
Go and soothe her, go on.
哗，盲唧都黎Disco喎
Oh, a blind men at a disco.
系呀，我哋黎听音乐吖嘛
We're here to listen to the music.
有冇人带一带我哋去厕所呀？
Can someone take me to the toilet?
周时劈呀，帮吓人喇
Chow Sze Pok help him.
吓，我？厕所喺边度呀
Me? Where's the toilet.
舞池对面吖嘛，黎喇，快啲去喇
The toilet's over there. It's opposite the dance floor, go now.
哦，行喇      唔该
- Get going. - Thank you.
唔该晒你呀
Thank you very much.
厕所，厕所，厕所
Toilet, toilet, toilet.
大表哥，唔驶惊架
Cousin don't worry.
嗱，你而家行前十步推门
Move forward 10 steps and push the door.
如果听到冇乜音乐呢，就可以疴架喇
When the music dies down just piss.
哦
Oh.
向前行十步就到厕所
Move forward 10 steps, the toilet.
十、九、八、七、六
10, 9, 8, 7, 6,
五、四、三、二、一
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
冇乜音乐声喎，系呢度喇
No more music, must be here.
可以疴喇
I'll do it here.
咁核突都可以拎得出黎唧
Oh, flashers.
嗱，你拎住
Well, hold it. Keep it.
你要咗佢喇
You keep it.
多谢
Thank you.
你系唔系有个弱智细佬架？
Have you got a mentally retarded younger brother?
哦，唔系，嗰个我大佬黎唧
No, he's my bigger brother.
佢后生过你好多呀
He's much younger than you.
话我老，整多几粒
Me, old, let me take a few more pills.
今晚呢好多谢大家 黎参加呢个劲舞比赛
Thank you for your participation tonight.
咁同时呢亦都好多谢呢几位舞蹈名家
We'd like to thank these famous dancers for acting
黎担任今晚唧评判
as our panel too.
好嘞，而家比赛正式开始咯喎
Well, let's start the competition.
开始喇
Ready?
喂...开始喇，开始喇
Hello, ready, ready.
而家我哋欢迎第一位参赛者，关公子
Now the first participant, Mr. Kwan.
哗，跳得好好呀
Oh, not bad.
坚叔你冇事吖嘛？
Are you alright Uncle Kin?
冇事，冇事
I'm alright.
好嘢
Good.
好嘢，好嘢
Great, great.
好嘞，而家欢迎第二位参赛朋友
Yes. Now the second participant...
刘定坚先生
Mr. Lau Ting Kin.
好嘢，好嘢
Great, great.
到你喇
It's yours term.
死喇，又收缩添
Damn I'm shrinking again.
你做咩呀？
What are you doing?
咁你点跳呀？
How can you dance then?
乜唔跳呀，我成副身家赌晒落去
Why not, I've betted everything on it.
唉吔，真系佢呀
Oh, it really is him.
弱智都黎参加，真系难得喇
Even a moron is participating.
起身喇，起身喇，姐姐支持你呀
Get up, get up, I'll back you up.
起身喇...
Get up.
各位，刘定坚先生系一位弱智人士
Ladies and gentlemen Mr. Lau Ting Kin is a moron.
佢今次参加比赛
He took part in this competition...
无非都系想筹啲钱俾弱智基金
to raise money for the mentally retarded.
我希望你哋有钱出钱 支持刘定坚先生
Please contribute in cash or in kind to support him.
钱呀
Money.
有钱执呀
Pennies from heaven.
哎吔！你赢咗喇
You've won, you've won.
你赢咗，你赢咗喇
姐姐真系佩服你唧毅力喇
I really admire your perseverance sister.
呢度一万银奖金，你唧
Here's the $10,000 prize.
多谢，多谢姐姐
Thank you sister.
姐姐呀，你唧金表好靓
Sister you have a very nice gold watch.
我又冇表带唧
I haven't got any watch.
呢只女装表黎架，唔啱你带架
It's a ladies watch, it's not for you.
姐姐，姐姐呀
Sister, sister.
好啰，好啰，你唔好喊吓
Well don't cry, don't cry.
你唔好喊吓
Don't cry.
嗱，我俾一万蚊你
Take this $10,000
你自己去买喇，吓
and buy one yourself.
多谢，多谢姐姐，多谢
Thank you, thank you sister.
姐夫呀，你谂清楚未架？
Brother-in-law have you thought it over?
唉，而家间间公司都兴迁拆喇
It's in vogue for every company to relocate.
咁关公子收购咗沾沾烧鸡鸭店
Once Mr. Kwan acquires Jim barbecue poultry restaurant...
喺万利士注册上市，股票一出
the company will be listed in Mannis with stocks issued.
我哋发达喇
We're going to be rich.
你哋仲可以搞埋移民添
And you may even process your immigration.
喺啰
Right.
咁万利士究竟喺边度黎架
Where's Mannis?
喺非洲，系一个世外桃源
In Africa, it's a men's paradise.
女人服从男人
Women are subordinate to men...
法律上男人可以娶十二个老婆
and men may legally take a dozen wives.
呀，咁我哋几时去呀？
When shall we go then?
好快，合约上指定你同你三个女
Soon. The contract stipulates that you,
仲有你姨仔文文
your 3 daughters and your sister-in-law Mun Mun...
喺万利士做足三年嘢
can get passports...
就可以攞护照嘞
once you've worked there for 3 years.
老细
Boss,
你请晒佢哋去万利士有乜作用呀？
what's with your idea of sending them all to Mannis?
班穷鬼同我作对，我就偏偏要赢
They confronted us and I must beat them.
万利士班差佬全部都系我唧人
All the cops in Mannis are my men...
有钱就恶晒
and money makes the mare run.
我要佢四条女嫁晒俾我
I want all his daughters to marry me.
玩完就卖俾啲黑鬼
After I get fed up with them I'll sell them to Negroes.
一定有问题
There must be something wrong.
哼，嗰个关公子仲奸过石坚
Of course, he's craftier than Sze Kin.
梗系有问题喇
There must be something wrong.
系啦，万利士都唔知喺边度
Right, who knows where Mannis is.
都唔知去唔得过唧，呵？
Is it worth taking the trip?
计我话呢，最好搵个人去查探吓先
We better send someone to do a survey.
不过呢个人选呢
But the man must be wise,
要又聪明、又机警、又好打
sagacious and a good fighter.
又靓仔、又英明神武咁先得唧
He must also be smart and brave.
呀，周时劈呀
Chow Sze Pok.
虽然我喺厕所呀
I overheard your compliment about me
我知你哋赞紧我
while I was in the toilet.
但系我系唔会去架
But I will never go there.
唔好谂我呀
Don't pick on me.
冇得上诉呀
You can't change your mind.
喂，朱玉干呀？你而家喺边呀？
Hey Dried Pork where are you now?
喂，坚叔呀，我已经黎咗万利士喇
Hello uncle Kin, I'm in Mannis.
我喺山顶打电话俾你唧
I'm calling from the peak.
喂，万利士弄唔弄呀？
Well how is it over there?
呢度简直系风景如画，世外桃源
It has a picturesque landscape like paradise.
讲你都唔信呀，呢度净系有靓女咋
Believe it or not there are only girls here.
我成个月呀都未见过男人
I haven't seen one man for a whole month.
哗，发达啰
Oh, we're lucky.
唔驶带咁多钱黎架
There's no need to bring to much money here.
我袋住十蚊美金，成个月都未驶完呀
US$10 for one whole month.
好似有自己友咁唧声喎，你等阵吓
Sounds like our friends, hold on.
有生番呀，我唔弄喇
Savages, I'm finished.
救命呀
Help.
唔去，合同都签咗咯噃
You must go now, you've already signed the contract.
喂，嗰度有生番个噃
Oh, there are savages over there.
咁咪即系叫我哋过去俾人烧黎食
Are we to go over there and been cooked for dinner?
你情我愿嗰噃
It's by mutual consent.
贱人
Tramp.
靓女，唔好噏得出就噏呀
Beautiful, don't talk nonsense.
我有大个证人喺度架
I've got a witness here.
第日去到万利士你就知我好架喇
When you're in Mannis you'll be grateful.
姐夫呀，咁我哋而家点呀？
Brother-in-law what shall we do now?
我唔知点呀？
How do I know?
话你听喇，虽然你对我咁衰呀
Listen, though you're bad to me
我都唔想你俾啲生番捉咗去当早餐食
I won't let you be eaten by savages.
咁喇，等我谂办法帮你哋搞弄佢喇
Let me try something to fix it for you.
唉，沾哥
Oh, Jim.
呵，你仲黎
Don't come here anymore.
我已经开间鸡鸭店黎避咗你啰喎
I've already opened a poultry restaurant to avoid you.
多谢你帮忙
Thank you for your help...
不过帮开一次再帮多一次啫
but help me once more.
我想开间黑记鸡鸭鱼旦档
I want to open a Kee Kei poultry and fish ball shop...
有鸡叫，有鱼旦卖
to sell chicken and fish balls.
想用五万蚊顶咗你间铺
I'll pay you $50,000 for your shop.
呵，而家恰我哋嘞喎，我哋有人照架
Don't bully us, we have protection.
吓，我哋有人照
We have protection.
边个照你呀？
We have a protector?
关公子啰
Mr. Kwan.
吓，就系啱啱出门口嗰个乸型呀？
That sissy man who just left?
我哋Big brother有财有势有皇气
Our big brother is rich, powerful and regal.
佢话最多从法律途径去解决唧啫
He claims he'll settle everything through legal channels.
好，我睇佢点巴闭法
Well, let me see how powerful he is.
听日中午十二点钟，喺呢度同佢讲数
Let's talk terms with him at noon tomorrow.
唉，唔系，系倾计
No, to talk only.
喂，你头先讲乜呀？
What did you say just now?
你都傻唧，佢哋一个靠法律
Don't be silly. One of them goes by the law,
一个靠黑社会唧势力
the other depends on his underworld influence.
我哋靠个脑去Fight吖嘛
Let's use our brains to fight them.
嗱，沾叔，你同关公子讲
Uncle Ji,
我哋系黑鬼冯照唧
tell Mr. Kwan we're protected by Darkie Fung.
叫佢听日晏昼十二点，黎呢度讲数
Tell him to come here to talk terms at noon tomorrow.
你就系黑鬼冯系嘛？
Aren't you Darkie Fung?
好话，你叫关公子呀
Yes, you must be Mr. Kwan.
咦，好似几个月前边部戏咁唧
Sounds like that movie several months ago.
唓，我喺金庸本鹿鼎记度抄出黎架嘛
I copied it from Chiu Yung's Lu Ting Chi.
一生欠债万千千
Up to my ears in debt my whole life.
削骨削肉也难填
I can't even be redeemed by flesh and blood.
若然追得紧
If the collector pursues too hard.
人命也关连
It could be fatal.
左唔还，右唔还，左唔还，右唔还
No repayment left and right, no repayment left and right.
无了期呀，无定期，无了期，无定期
Dragged on indefinitely, indefinitely.
本来我都唔想暴露身分
I didn't want to expose my identity
不过到咗呢个地步
but at this crucial moment
大佬，你同我搞弄佢
I need your help buddy.
有钱好巴闭呀，连你都屈埋呀
What's so special about money? Even you ingratiate yourself.
黑社会呢，我就未惊过，我有大把钱
I don't fear the underworld, I have lots of money.
你得一个单位啫
You only have one unit.
我可以出钱请十个单位联手黎對冧你
I could pay to hire 10 units to gang against you.
佢财雄势大，好汉不吃眼前亏呀
He's rich and powerful, don't get involved.
老细，你有头有面，同啲黑社会争
Boss you're a notable, don't quarrel with the underworld.
冇着数喎
It's not worthwhile.
不过万事有商量，唔弄讲到弄啫
Anything can be talked over.
大佬，千祈唔好同佢菺呀
Big brother don't compromise.
一于對冧佢呀，我哋班人黎紧架
Finish him off, our men are coming.
老细，趁佢啲马未到，快啲擝喇
Act now boss, before his men arrive.
郁佢
Get him.
万事以和为贵，唔好冲动，唔好冲动
Peace benefits all. Don't act on impulses.
唉，冷静啲，冷静啲
Keep cool, keep cool.
嗱，黑鬼冯
Well Darkie Fung...
我哋劝过我哋大佬架嘞
we tried to persuade our big brother.
补番十万蚊你算和数
He'll pay $100,000 once and for all.
以后河水不犯井水
We won't interfere in each others business.
你唔搵人搞佢得嘞
From now on don't get men to cope with him. Okay?
咁好唔好？
How about this?
嗱，关公子，我哋劝大佬补番十万银
Mr. Kwan we'll persuade him to pay you $100,000
你交番张合约出黎
and you have the contract cancelled.
唔系见镬打镬架，咁有冇问题先
Otherwise we'll fight to the end. Okay?
十万，Ok
Okay, $100,000.
Ok
Okay.
老细，收住十万银先
Boss, take this now don't stand to suffer.
好汉不吃眼前亏呀
Take it and forget it,
有水收呀，算呀，佢哋好似有料到噃
they seem to be after something.
好喇
Okay.
坚叔，我哋讲弄数喇
Hey Uncle Kin we've come to terms,
攞住廿万黎先喇
give me $200,000.
黎吖，快啲喇
Come on, quick.
呢次真系大出血
This time it's like a grand sale.
刘定坚，我以前对你咁衰
Lau Ting Kin I was bad to you
你而家仲肯帮我
and you've helped me.
我真系唔知点讲至好
I really don't know how to thank you.
你唔驶讲喇，你知得喇
I'm glad you understand.
不过我话你听呀
But remember
我借钱俾你收番半分息架
I charge 5% interest for my loan.
企喺度，唔好周围腾啦
Stay there, don't go anywhere.
合约呢？俾佢
- Where's the contract? - Give it to him.
钱呢      冇问题
- The money? - No problem.
收咗钱喺后门走嘞
Leave through the back door
费事班人番黎撞到误会呀
or they may misunderstand when they meet you.
哗，咩？乜咁高兴两班人喺度呀？
Oh, how hilarious with two groups of people here.
唔好乱噏嘢呀
Stop that nonsense.
你咪话黑鬼冯逼你搬唧
Didn't you say Darkie Fung forced you to move?
你又话关公子逼口水沾搬去万利士架
And you said Mr. Kwan forced Bluffer Jim to move to Mannis.
做乜而家Friend番晒呀
Why aren't you on good terms now?
吓
Why?
讲清楚先呀
Let's straighten this out now.
黑鬼冯，你系唔系佢哋大佬
Darkie Fung are you his big brother?
我以为你系佢哋大佬咋
I thought you were his big brother.
咩话？点我
What? You fooled me.
抢番份合约
Get the contract back.
接住
Catch.
黑鬼冯，帮手抢，抢到三十万
Darkie Fung give me a hand, $300,000 if you get it.
抢到三十万，上
$300,000 if you get it, come on.
哗，你哋咁矛架
Oh, you really are tough.
喂，驶唔驶帮拖呀？
Hey, do you need a hand?
梗系要啦，快啲黎喇
Of course, come on.
帮拖五千
$5,000 if I help you.
你去死啦
To hell with you.
唉，报警吖，报警五旧咋
I'll call the police, only $500 if I call the police.
我俾呀，我俾呀，我俾呀
I'll pay you, I'll pay you.
你们不要玩我的胶水
Don't take my glue for playing.
还想走，捉着他...
He want to leave, catch him...
我们来救你
We will help you.
打佢...
Beat him.
抵你死
You deserve it.
你们没事吗？
Are you all right?
我哋而家应该点呀？
What shall we do now?
咁点呀？好放咗我添呀
Just let me go.
如果唔系阵间差人黎到
If the police arrive...
我就话你同黑社会合谋
I'll accuse you of conspiring with the underworld and blackmail.
恐吓、ザ索，监都有得你坐呀
You may get jailed.
哎吔，咁多嘢讲，黐埋你把口嗱
Nonsense, I'll glue your mouth.
睇吓边个仲敢讲嘢
See if anyone dares to talk anymore.
我有计
I have an idea.
快啲吖
Hurry up.
喂，等等，等我开闸先
Hey, wait till I open the gate.
黑社会头子？
A gang boss?
黑社会职员？
An underworld clerk?
群殴定搞基呀？
Kun Au Ting having a gay affair?
黑社会入会仪式
Underworld membership ceremony.
亚Sir呀，佢哋讲咩呀？
What are they murmuring about sir?
唔系，佢哋哑唧
They're mute.
哑都入得黑社会咩？
Can a mute man join the underworld.
哑唔入得黑社会咩？
Why not?
救命呀
Help us.
救我哋喇
亚Sir呀，好彩你哋黎得快咋
Luckily you came fast sir
如果唔系我哋俾啲社会屈我哋入会喇
or they would have forced us into their membership.
拉晒佢哋
Take them away too.
拉晒佢哋喇，拉晒佢哋喇
Take them all away, take them all away.
点解佢哋一个二个黐晒喺度架？
Why are they all out of their minds?
唔知喎，我哋都绑晒喺度
No idea, we've all been tied up.
拉晒佢哋番差馆
Take them all to the police station.
Yes，sir
Yes sir.
上黎，上黎...
Come up, come up.
喂，快上去
Hey, Come up.
闩闸，快啲
Shut the gate quickly.
收队，收队，走
Dismissed, dismissed. Go.
亚Sir呀，亚Sir，你而家拉晒佢哋
You've taken them away sir.
第日我哋驶唔驶上堂做证人架？
Do we have to testify in court then?
咁唧款抬上法庭
If we can't convict them
都告唔入系黑社会
the way they are,
我哋仲驶做差人唧
we don't deserve to be called policemen.
唔驶上庭喇
There's no need to go to court.
拜拜
Bye bye.
唉，咁真系惨呀
So much the worse.
想搵啲证人费都冇埋
We can't even get fees as witnesses.
喂，你都唔好恨啲证人费喇
Don't covet that.
嗱，我哋一世人冤家
We're enemies...
第一次合作咁愉快
but it's the first time we've cooperated.
不如继续合作落去喇
Let's continue our cooperation.
嗱，我哋可以开间坚沾鸡鸭火锅店
We can open a Kin-Jim Poultry hot pot restaurant.
实搵水架，搵咗水咪大家去移民啰
We'll make money for sure and when we do we can emigrate.
好唔好呀？好呀
- What do you say? - Good idea.
（一九九零年，香港）
"1990, Hong Kong"
大镬饭，大镬饭，香港人民大镬饭
Big pan rice, big pan rice, Hong Kong's big pan rice.
香港人民大镬饭，系香港人民唧食堂
Hong Kong's big pan rice is in the Hong Kong people's canteen.
我哋有蒸饭、炒饭、冷饭、饭焦
We've got steamed, fried, cold, burnt,
汤饭、一旧饭，瓣瓣都有
soup and dumpling rice.
入到黎香港人民大镬饭
When in Hong Kong people's canteen...
你只会想到食饭
you want nothing...
因为，根本冇其他唧嘢食
but rice because there's nothing else available.
大镬饭，大镬饭，好难食足100蚊
Big pan rice, big pan rice.
（非洲）
"Africa"
要兄弟定要黄金
You want brothers or gold?
黄金，黄金
Gold, Gold?
要兄弟定要黄金
Brothers or gold?
黄金，黄金
Gold, gold.
如果俾你，要兄弟定要黄金
And you, you want brothers or gold?
你拣边样？黄金，黄金
- What do you want? - Gold, gold.
大表哥呀，你收埋咁多黑鬼做咩嘢？
Cousin, why do you keep so many blacks?
佢哋冚巴郎都系黑之乌孖
They're all so dark,
唔做黑社会，做咩呀？
what else can they do but be underworld members.
只准要黄金，不准要兄弟
You must choose gold not brothers.
黄金，黄金...
Gold, gold.
（三藩市）
"San Francisco"
不好意思
Excuse me.
表演何时开始？
May I wait a show time.
表演快开始了
Show time is coming, coming.
看看
Look, look.
有冇搞错呀？咁唧嘢都好睇唧
What's wrong, what's there to see?
各位
Gentlemen
各位先生
and gentlemen,
表演开始
show time.
哗，好嘢
Oh, great.
点解要移民，点解要两头腾
Why emigrate? Why fuss?
宁愿去金山洗大银 费事招呼啲解放军
I'd rather be a dish washer in the USA than serve the PLA.
民主自由都无谓等
No need to wait for democracy and freedom.
冇胆对住啲坦克阵
No guts to face the tanks.
点解要移民
Why emigrate?